So far, you've done a bunch of things with files and directories.
目前为止 你已对文件和目录执行了一堆操作
But where do files come from in the first place?
但是文件最初从何而来的呢？
Well, they come from the web.
它们来自网路
There's a shell command to download a file from the web.
有一个 shell 命令用来从网络下载文件
That command is curl,
此命令为 curl
that stands for C URL,
代表 C URL
as in see a web page.
即 see URL（查看网页）
Whoever named that, ha ha, yes, very funny.
无论是谁命名的 哈哈 的确很有趣
You can use curl to get any web page,
你可以使用 curl 来获取任何网页
but what it does is to show you the source code to
但它的作用是向你显示页面的
the page which is kind of cool but not always directly useful.
源代码 这挺酷的 但并非直接有用
We try to get http://google.com,
比如我们想转至 http://google.com
it's actually showing us some HTML that really wants us to go someplace else.
它会向我们显示一些 HTML 但实际上会将我们导航到别处
You need to add a little option to curl,
你需要给 curl 添加一个选项
curl dash big L means follow
curl -L 表示遵循
redirects and then we'll see the source code to the actual google.com homepage.
重定向 然后我们将看到转至实际 google.com 主页的源代码
Ha! there we go, this is
哈！这就好了 这是
the compressed JavaScript source code to the google.com homepage.
到 google.com 主页的压缩 JavaScript 源代码
It's got things in there like,
它里面的内容有
I'm Feeling Lucky and Google search.
“I'm Feeling Lucky”和“Google Search”
This is a lot like what you'd see if you opened up
这跟你在浏览器开发工具中
the View Source in the browser dev tools.
打开 View Source（查看源代码）时会看到的差不多
So, that's kind of handy for checking out web sites,
所以 这很便于查看网站
but curl is very useful for downloading files or pages by URL.
但是 curl 非常适合通过 URL 下载文件或页面
To get it to write to a file instead of displaying to the terminal,
要使其写入文件而不是显示给终端
we use the dash little o option.
我们使用 -o 选项
We say, curl dash little o followed by
我们用 curl-o 后跟
the file name that we'd like it to save under, like google.html.
我们想要保存在其之下的文件名称 如 google.html
This is actually a really common pattern for shell commands.
这实际上是 shell 命令的一个很常见的模式
Start with the name of the command followed by
以命令名称开头 后跟
some options like dash little o google.html
一些选项 如 -o google.html
and dash capital L and then followed
及 -L 然后后跟
by the object that we actually want to operate on, like the URL.
我们实际想要操作的对象 如 URL
We run this, curl will show a little progress message while it's downloading.
我们运行它 curl 将在下载时显示一些进程消息
When it's finished, we just get our shell prompt back.
完成时 我们会回到 shell 提示符
It's pretty common for Unix programs to not
一个很常见的情况是 如果 Unix 程序运行成功 则
display any logs or done message if they run successfully.
不会显示任何日志或完成消息
But it did run successfully.
但它确实运行成功了
And there's the file that it created, google.html.
这是它创建的文件 google.html